### Contact

judy.murphy29@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/judy-murphyrn-facmi-lfhimss-faan-4066442 (LinkedIn)

www.tigersummit.com/ (Other) coursedocs.umaryland.edu/ Projects/amia/pioneers.htm (Other) www.healthit.gov/ (Other)

### Top Skills

**Informatics** 

**EHR** 

Healthcare Information Technology

### Certifications

Healthcare Insights and Solutions (Platinum)

### Honors-Awards

Recipient of the 2018 HIMSS Most Influential Women in Health IT Award

### **Publications**

An Introduction to Nursing Informatics: Evolution & Innovation

# Judy Murphy, RN, FACMI, LFHIMSS, FAAN

Chief Nursing Officer (CNO) - IBM Global Healthcare Lake Elmo, Minnesota

## Summary

Judy Murphy is Chief Nursing Officer (CNO) at IBM Global Healthcare, where she is responsible for building relationships and expanding business across the healthcare industry. She is strategic advisor to clients and puts together health IT solutions in order to improve health and healthcare, lower costs, and ease clinical workload. She is a member of the IBM Industry Academy and is a much sought after consultant and speaker on the digital transformation of healthcare. Her expertise lies in advancing tools for consumer engagement, provider enablement and analytics for population health, cognitive computing to support a learning health system, and promoting the use of mobile to streamline workflow. She has a long-standing reputation of patient advocacy and maintaining a patient-centric point of view, and approaches her work with unyielding energy as well as passion and commitment to the transformation enabled by technology.

Prior to working at IBM, Ms. Murphy was CNO and Deputy National Coordinator for Programs and Policy at the Office of the National Coordinator for Health IT (ONC) in Washington D.C. In these roles, she led federal efforts to assist health care providers in adopting health information technology to improve care and to promote consumers' greater understanding and use of health information technology for their own health.

Ms. Murphy came to ONC with more than 25 years of health informatics experience at Aurora Health Care in Wisconsin, an integrated delivery network with 15 hospitals, 120 ambulatory centers, and over 30,000 employees. As Vice President-EHR Applications, she led their EHR program since 1995, when Aurora was one of the early adopters of health IT. She has experience with the implementation of both Epic and Cerner in the acute and ambulatory care settings.

Ms. Murphy is a tireless volunteer who has been involved in many aspects of organizational work at AMIA and HIMSS, serving on numerous committees as well as their Board of Directors.

### Experience

IBM Healthcare
Chief Nursing Officer (CNO)
October 2014 - Present (5 years 10 months)
Greater Minneapolis-St. Paul Area

Helping make people's lives better using Health IT.

Alliance for Nursing Informatics
Co-Chair
January 2011 - January 2017 (6 years 1 month)

Serving to ensure that all Nursing Informatics Organizations have a forum to convene and organize, in order to speak with one voice.

U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) 2 years 11 months

ONC Chief Nursing Officer (CNO) & Director, Office of Clinical Quality and Safety

June 2014 - October 2014 (5 months)

Washington DC

At the Office of the National Coordinator for Health IT (ONC), responsible for coordinating federal efforts regarding health IT-enabled quality policy and standards, integrating standardized measurement and clinical decision support for quality improvement, advancing usability of software and hardware, ensuring that health IT makes care safer, and improving the safety of Health IT.

ONC Deputy National Coordinator for Programs and Policy December 2011 - June 2014 (2 years 7 months)

At the Office of the National Coordinator for Health IT (ONC), coordinated federal efforts to assist health care providers in adopting health information technology to improve care and worked to promote consumers' greater understanding and use of health information technology for their own health. Responsible for administering the federally-funded HITECH (Heath Information Technology for Economic and Clinical Health) programs for: 62 Regional

Extension Centers, 56 State-Designated Entities for Health Information Exchange, 17 Beacon Programs, 4 Workforce Training Programs, Electronic Health Record Certification, Consumer eHealth, and the Health IT Resource Center.

#### **HIMSS**

Member Board Of Directors March 2012 - June 2014 (2 years 4 months)

Served as an elected Board Member; and then as a liaison between ONC and the HIMSS Board of Directors, working on topics and issues that crossed both organizations.

Aurora Health Care

27 years 1 month

VP - EHR Applications
January 2005 - November 2011 (6 years 11 months)

Milwaukee, Wisconsin

Led Aurora's EHR program and managed the organization's achievement of Stage 1 EHR Meaningful Use, with incentive payments beginning in September 2011. Aurora Health Care is an integrated delivery network with 15 hospitals, 120 ambulatory centers, home health agencies and over 30,000 employees in Wisconsin. Was responsible for their EHR program since 1995, when Aurora was one of the early adopters of health IT. Implemented both Cerner and Epic EHR software in the hospital, outpatient and ambulatory settings.

Director, Clinical Application Development January 1996 - December 2004 (9 years) Milwaukee, Wiscsonsin

Manager, Clinical Information Systems
May 1993 - December 1995 (2 years 8 months)
Milwaukee, Wisconsin

Clinical Systems Project Manager May 1989 - May 1993 (4 years 1 month) Milwaukee, Wisconsin

Senior Clinical Systems Analyst November 1984 - May 1989 (4 years 7 months) Milwaukee, Wisconsin AMIA (American Medical Informatics Association) Member Board Of Directors January 2004 - December 2009 (6 years)

Elected member of the AMIA Board of Directors.

Saint Luke's Medical Center Registered Nurse June 1975 - November 1984 (9 years 6 months) Milwaukee, Wisconsin

Staff Nurse, Asst Head Nurse, and Nursing Inservice Instructor

## Education

Alverno College BSN, Nursing · (1971 - 1975)

Pius XI Catholic High School high school · (1967 - 1971)